as well as VHB937 in ALS. So exciting, I think, second half coming up. Solid first half of the
year and looking forward to continued progress in the months ahead. So with that, I'll hand it over
to Mukul.
Thank you very much, Vas. And good morning, good afternoon, everyone on the call.
I will now share more details on the financials for the second quarter.
And as a reminder, my comments has always referred to growth rates in constant currencies,
unless otherwise noted. Turning to slide 18. So in the second quarter, net sales grew 1% to $14.4
billion, while core operating income was flat at $5.9 billion. This is as our sales growth
driver for the second quarter. So we're going to see some improvement in the second half. So with that, I'll hand it over to Mukul.
Thank you very much.
Thank you for welcome.
Thank you, Mark.
avidity cost with a lower gross margin being offset by productivity gains. It's worth noting
that Q2 is generally a stronger margin quarter when we look at the phasing across the whole year.
Free cash flow for the second quarter was at $5.6 billion, which is in line with expectations.
Worth to note that Q2 results were also positively impacted by some one-time phasing items,
which we'll reverse in the second half. Together, these items positively impacted
net sales by approximately one percentage point and core operating income by about five percentage
points. And then for the first half of the year, net sales declined 2%, core operating income
declined 7%, and the core operating margin declined 2.3 percentage points to 39.4%.
Free cash flow for the first half of the year stood at $8.9 billion.
Turning to slide 19, we remain committed to our shareholder-friendly capital allocation strategy
that has served us well as a company, balancing discipline, growth investments in the business
with meaningful capital distribution. In Q2, we continue to execute multiple bolt-on M&A and BD